

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Total Experience: 20 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Information Technology]

Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Designation: Lead Unix Consultant

Current Company: Wipro Technologies

Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Pune
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance
Role: System Admin

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Linux Administration, Solaris Administration, Veritas Volume Manager, Veritas Cluster Server, ZFS, VXVM, LVM, NFS Server, VMware Vsphere, Unix Shell Scripting, Redhat Linux, Red Hat Enterprise Linux,

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

#### **Summary**

\* Aqualified and highly technically certified visionary professional offering 20 years of notable contributions in the entire gamut of providing IT Solutions & support covering Networking, Systems Administration with rich years of experience in Solaris System Administration environment and Linux System Administration environment with Virtualization and High Availability Clustering in Linux / Unix environments.

\* Certifications entails from Oracle (Sun) , Red Hat, Symantec (Veritas) , VMWARE, Cisco and ITIL , AWS .

\* Achievement oriented professional with excellent people management skills and an ability to manage change with ease

### **Work Experience**

Wipro Technologies as Lead Unix Consultant Dec 2015 to Till Date

Key Result Areas:

Currently working for a different Wipro Engagement since May '20

Following experience for a Global Banking client project of Wipro from Apr '18 till Apr '20

- \* Performing post config changes on Linux servers
- \* Performing OS upgrades of RHEL 7 AND RHEL 6 using HPSA Policies and HPSA Tool.
- \* Installation / configuration of Infoscale Veritas Storage Foundation and Infoscale Enterprise Veritas Cluster server Products on Linux servers
- \* Performing extension and creation of VxVM and LVM filesystem in Linux
- \* Taking part in Production and DR testing activities
- \* Performing reboots of Linux Physical on HP Proliant servers and Virtual servers in VMVARE.

Following experience for a UK Banking Client Project of Wipro from Dec '15 to Mar '18

- $^{\star}$  Working in UK project as Unix migration analyst (P2V/V2V/L & S/SAN Migration ) for a leading financial banking client of WIPRO
- \* Unix/Linux storage Migration activities with Veritas Storage Foundation and Veritas Cluster server
- \* Performing physical to virtual and virtual to virtual migrations of Linux Servers via VMWARE tools (VMWARE Converter, vSphere Web Client) and Unix datacenter migrations of Linux / Solaris servers with Veritas Storage Foundation and Veritas Cluster server.
- \* Undertaking servers hardware checks and ensuring resolution to hardware issues on priority before Unix migration
- \* Undertaking storage / clusters checks and getting SAN / Cluster issues resolved prior to scheduled Unix migrations
- \* Engaged in network requirement checks prior to scheduled Unix migrations; performing OS (Solaris / Linux) checks prior to scheduled Unix migrations
- \* Preparing Unix/Linux SAN Sheets prior to scheduled Unix migrations

## **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld Hardware Platform

Sun Mdrange and entry level and High end servers (v440,T1000,M5000,M3000, 6800,280R / 480R , Sunfire 880 etc)

Providing following SLAbound 24x7 Unix/Linux system administration support offshore Support to US and Europe (Telecom / Insurance / Banking) clients.

- System Administration for Solaris 8 and 9 / 10 OS on Sun Servers including hardware support
- System Administration for Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4, 5, 6 OS on HP Proliant Servers, VMWARE, Cisco UCS including HP Proliant / Cisco UCS hardware support
- Providing first and second level support for VERITAS Netbackup Issue's
- Veritas cluster Administration
- Creation of VCS Service Groups
- Failover test of VCS Service Groups to remote and local nodes
- Extension of VCS Filesystems
- VCS user creation with Administrator / Operator priviledges
- Performing VCS upgrade and applying VCS and Storage foundation patches
- Decommissioning of Filesystems / Storage LUNS in VCS / Veritas Volume Manager.
- User administration in LDAP
- Handling Sun Server builds and zone builds in Solaris
- Providing BCV backup support for Oracle databases hosted on Solaris Servers.
- Handling Storage Migration on sun servers in wwm, svm, zfs
- Creation and mounting of ZFS Filesystems, setting quota, sharing ZFS resource in NFS.
- Configuring of new Storage LUNs on sun servers provisioned by storage team according to storage design sheet and creating file systems.
- Resolving Storage link failure issue on Sun Servers using multipating softwares
- (EMC Powerpath, VERITAS Dynamic Multipathing, MPIXO)
- For a US leading Financial organization Leading offshore Pre Provisioning team for coordinating racking/stacking console configuration of servers in datacenters, ensuring network readiness, Applying Base Linux OS on IBMHP/Dell servers, Hardware / Network vendor co-ordination for resolving critical server issues.
- Extension of HPUX wfs filesystems in LVM

## Capgemini Consulting India Pvt Ltd. as Senior Unix Consultant

May 2007 to Oct 2008

Hardware Platform

Sun Mdrange and entry level servers (e.g Sun fire v120, v240R / 280R / 480R, Sunfire 880), 4800 Domain, Sun Storage A1000

Role & Contribution

- -Senior System Administrator Providing SLA bound 24x7 offshore Support to Capgemini customers in UK
- Been to UK (London) for 2 months for knowledge transfer Phase for supporting Capgemini dients through Offshore Support.
- System Administration for Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 OS on HP Servers including hardware support
- System Administration for Solaris 8 and 9 OS on Sun Servers including hardware support
- Providing first and second level support for VERITAS Netbackup Issue's
- Data restoration through Atempto Time Navigator backup
- Troubleshooting BCV backup issue's
- Configuring of new Storage LUNs on sun servers provisioned by storage team according to storage design sheet and creating file systems in in VXVM, SVM, ZFS

## Larsen &Toubro InfoTech as Sun Solaris System Administrator

Oct 2005 to May 2007

Role & Contribution

-Team member Providing 24x7 Offshore Support to Audible IT Operations

Providing SLA bound Level 1, 2, 3 Solaris Support to Audible Inc including Administration and Management of: Solaris 10 Operating System

Applications

Web servers

Sun Hardware Support

Continuous monitoring of availability and performance metrics of all Sun servers.

Performing scheduled Bouncing/Restart of Solaris Production Apache Web//Broadvision/Interaction Manager Servers.

Monitoring Of Apache Web /Tomcat Web/Broadvision/Interaction Manager Servers Specific Processes on Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers Using the CA Unicenter NSM tool to ensure 99% uptime of www.audible.com,www.audible.fr,www.audible.uk,www.audible.de sites

Resolving Permission issues on Files/Directories on Solaris Production / Development/Test environment Servers.

Scheduling CRONJOBs on Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers.

Resolving issues related to Unix Filesystem Full .

Resolving Hyperion Performance issue's by stopping and restarting the Briosuit Services.

Resolving issues related to FTP file upload issues to Audible FTP Servers

Resolving issues related to the Snapper Tool (Ahome grown tool built by Audible IT Operations to copy files using Secure Copy (scp) between Production/Test/Development environments.

Killing Application/User Processes consuming high memory/cpu resource on Solaris Production / Development / Test environment Servers.

Creating and Deletion of Unix Accounts on Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers.

Mounting NFS File Systems on Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers.

Resolving VPN/RSA SECUREID TACACS issues for remote access to Audible internal Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers

Adding Network Static Routes on Solaris Production Servers

Configuring of new Storage LUNs on sun servers provisioned by storage team and creating file systems in vxvm, svm ₹s.

Resolving Unix Filesystem full issues.

Resolving Hyperion Performance issues by restarting Briosuit services

On Solaris Production servers.

Troubleshooting SAVBA issues for accessing Solaris File System shares

On Production / Development /Test environment Servers through Windows Desktops.

Granting SUDO Access to users on Solaris Production / Development / Test environment Servers.

Monitoring resource availability, abnormal termination, and cycle start and end times for scheduled batch processing usina CA-Unicenter

.....g ...........

Performing or assisting the application team in performing production batch restarts and reruns.

Manitoring real time performance using CA system management tools and resolving system reso.

Monitoring real-time performance using CA system management tools and resolving system resource and performance problems of 150 Production and 40 Development and Test Environment Servers using CA Unicenter NSM and SLMO tools and attending to ServiceDesk Trouble Tickets.

Analyzing historical performance data to isolate or identify potential performance issues using the Computer Associates SLMO Portal.

Responding to Hardware (CPU/Memory/Power Supply) Failure Email Alerts on Solaris Production / Development /Test environment Servers through ALOM (Sun Advanced Lights Out Manager) and logging a Call with Sun Mcrosystems Hardware Support for replacement of Parts.

^ Back to Top

#### **Education**

UG: Diploma (Industrial Electronics) from BTE maharashtra in 1998

 $\hbox{PG: MBA/PGDM (Information Technology) from United Business Institutes in {\bf 2012} \\$ 

^ Back to Top

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
ORACLE SUN Entry Level, Solaris 8/9.0/10			
HP Proliant Blade Servers, CISCO UCS			
RedHat Linux 4,5,6,Unix			
Oracle9i: SQL,Apache web server			
VERITA Netbackup , UFSdump,Tar			
Solaris IP Filter, Linux IP Tables			
REDHAT LINUX	7,6	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Solaris Administration	10	2015	11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
VERITAS CLUSTER SERVER	7	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
VERITAS VOLUME MANAGER	7	2020	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓	
hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓	
marathi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓	

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

# Work Authorization

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.